<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Topical Studies on BJWry</title>
    <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Topical Studies on BJWry</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>The MIT License (MIT) Copyright © 2020 BJWry</copyright><atom:link href="https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2015-03-24-predestination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2015-03-24-predestination/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/armageddon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/armageddon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/the-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/the-church/</guid>
      <description>https://www.biblestudytools.com/bible-study/topical-studies/what-is-the-church-according-to-the-bible.html What Is the Church? It&amp;rsquo;s Role and Purpose According to the Bible Pastor Luis Ángel Díaz-Pabón October 22, 2019
What Is the Church?
It&amp;rsquo;s Role and Purpose According to the Bible “Church” is the translation of the Greek term ekklesia, and is used in the New Testament to identify the community of believers in Jesus Christ. It literally means “assembly,” “congregation,” or “meeting.” A similar term was used in the Old Testament referring to experiences such as “the day of the assembly,” “the Lord’s congregation,” or “meeting before the Lord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angels</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/angels/</guid>
      <description>Angels# When were angels created?# For by Him all things were created, both in the heavens and on earth, visible and invisible, whether thrones or dominions or rulers or authorities—all things have been created through Him and fo Thus the heavens and the earth were completed, and all their hosts. Gen 2:1
Angels were created by God. The question is when?
My contention is that the angels had to be created during the six days although the Bible doesn&amp;rsquo;t say explicitly which day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armageddon</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/armageddon-zech6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/armageddon-zech6/</guid>
      <description>My notes on Armageddon# Where does Armageddon come from?
It is a Greek translation of har-megiddo
Har means hill or mountain.
the the Valley of Jezreel is what lies near
HISTORY
Megiddo controlled a narrow strategic stretch of road called the Via Maris, &amp;ldquo;the Way of the Sea,&amp;rdquo; a major international highway in the ancient world. This road stretched from Egypt in the south to Babylon in Mesopotamia, linking the major empires and trade routes of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biblical Covenants</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/biblical_covenants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/biblical_covenants/</guid>
      <description>Biblical Convenants# Establishing a preliminary understanding# In order to arrive at a proper understanding of the biblical covenants, we will take a step back and see the general usage and importance of the term &amp;ldquo;covenant&amp;rdquo;.# Although we have many external sources (i.e. dictionaries, archaeological data, lexicons, historical records) that help us acquire a better understanding, we will not go to those first.# 2. A Scriptural principle: If the topic is to be considered important within the teaching of Scripture, the Bible will provide us sufficient usage and background to gain a sufficient understanding of that particular topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confession of Sins</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/confession-of-sins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/confession-of-sins/</guid>
      <description>Confession of Sins# What the Scripture teaches# Spiritual Separation# Then the LORD God called to the man, and said to him, &amp;ldquo;Where are you?&amp;rdquo; Genesis 3:9
Relational Separation# While the Father-child relation cannot broken with God, communion can.# When is fellowship broken between the believer and God?# 2Co 6:14 Do not be bound together with unbelievers; for what partnership have righteousness and lawlessness, or what fellowship has light with darkness?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2021-07-27-daniel.6.18-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2021-07-27-daniel.6.18-28/</guid>
      <description>Daniel# Chapter 6 ends the historical section Darius had no alternative but to enforce the law he&amp;rsquo;d been tricked to make. This was the law of the Medes and the Persians. No one could revoke this law. Yet, they will learn, there is one who is sovereign over men who is above any Medo-Persian law. Daniel 6:18 Darius&amp;rsquo;s Sleepless night# Daniel 6:18# Dan 6:18 Then the king went off to his palace and spent the night fasting, and no entertainment was brought before him; and his sleep fled from him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 3:1-12</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2020-06-08-daniel-31-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2020-06-08-daniel-31-12/</guid>
      <description>This is the account of Nebuchadnezzar&amp;rsquo;s Image - False Worship
Man by default is religious. He will bow to something. God created man in his image. Mankind creates gods in their image. Romans 1:18-32
Worshipping God in our own way is also adultery.
Even though we might not bow down to any statue we can &amp;lsquo;bow&amp;rsquo; to gods in our hearts and minds.
Why did Nebuchadnezzar build this image? He was thinking about this since God spoke to him in the dream and visions, except he distorted it to his own benefit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with Pain</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/dealing_with_pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/dealing_with_pain/</guid>
      <description>Learning from Grief# It&amp;rsquo;s easy to doubt God when things don&amp;rsquo;t go well (Psalm 77:1-9) Knowing God&amp;rsquo;s true self provides a framework around our chaos (Psalm 77:10-14) Christ is our life (Psalm 77:15) Psalm 77# I. Psalm 77:1-6 Asaph doubts God# (For the choir director; according to Jeduthun. A Psalm of Asaph.)
Psa 77:1 My voice rises to God, and I will cry aloud; My voice rises to God, and He will hear me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galatians 1:11-24</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/galatians-111-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/galatians-111-24/</guid>
      <description>Gal 1:11 For I would have you know, brethren, that the gospel which was preached by me is not according to man.
Gal 1:12 For I neither received it from man, nor was I taught it, but I received it through a revelation of Jesus Christ.
Gal 1:13 For you have heard of my former manner of life in Judaism, how I used to persecute the church of God beyond measure and tried to destroy it;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homiletics</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/homiletics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/homiletics/</guid>
      <description>I. Content
- Providing clarity on the purpose of the passage - Analyzing the passage in context - Utilizing Bible references and supporting passages - Drives listeners back to the text of Scripture
II. Organization
- Provides an engaging introduction - Effectively traces the author&amp;rsquo;s flow of thought - Makes smooth transitions from point to point - Finishes with an effective conclusion
III. Rhetoric (the art of persuasion)
- Builds credibility, transparency, and personal examples - Connects well with listeners - Explains concepts using Scriptural reasoning</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>install Jekyll on MacOS Big Sur</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2020-06-11-install-jekyll-on-macos-big-sur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2020-06-11-install-jekyll-on-macos-big-sur/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t use the THIS for ruby. Go to step 2 first!# The instructions provided at the jekyll site did not work for me on MacOS (and many others do not recommend it). It is not the correct way. DO NOT USE THESE:
https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/macos/ I can&amp;rsquo;t even begin to say how hard it has been to correct the issues this caused on my machine.
One has to be a Ruby scientist to know how to correct it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Israel in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/israel-egypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/israel-egypt/</guid>
      <description>How long was Israel in Slavery?# The Israelites were actually only in Egypt for 215 years. Joseph and his family moved to Egypt 215 years after the promise is given to Abram.
Different dates given# Then the Lord said to Abram, “Know for certain that your offspring will be sojourners in a land that is not theirs and will be servants there, and they will be afflicted for 400 years.” (Genesis 15:13)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesus mismo-nuestra propiciación</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/jesus-mismo-nuestra-propiciacio%CC%81n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/jesus-mismo-nuestra-propiciacio%CC%81n/</guid>
      <description>Dios exigió la expiación y la proveyó”. Fue “por la gracia de Dios, Él pudo gustar la muerte por todos” (Heb. 2:9).
1Jn 2:2 Él mismo es la propiciación por nuestros pecados, y no solo por los nuestros, sino también por los del mundo entero.
1Jn 4:10 En esto consiste el amor: no en que nosotros hayamos amado a Dios, sino en que Él nos amó a nosotros y envió a Su Hijo como propiciación por nuestros pecados.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John 11:1-23</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/john-11.1-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/john-11.1-23/</guid>
      <description>Joh 11:1 Now a certain man was sick, Lazarus of Bethany, the village of Mary and her sister Martha. Joh 11:2 It was the Mary who anointed the Lord with ointment, and wiped His feet with her hair, whose brother Lazarus was sick. Joh 11:3 So the sisters sent word to Him, saying, &amp;ldquo;Lord, behold, he whom You love is sick.&amp;rdquo; Joh 11:4 But when Jesus heard this, He said, &amp;ldquo;This sickness is not to end in death, but for the glory of God, so that the Son of God may be glorified by it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John 11:35-48</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/john-11.35-48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/john-11.35-48/</guid>
      <description>Joh 11:35 Jesus wept. Joh 11:36 So the Jews were saying, &amp;ldquo;See how He loved him!&amp;rdquo; Joh 11:37 But some of them said, &amp;ldquo;Could not this man, who opened the eyes of the blind man, have kept this man also from dying?&amp;rdquo; Jesus Raises Lazarus
Joh 11:38 So Jesus, again being deeply moved within, *came to the tomb. Now it was a cave, and a stone was lying against it. Joh 11:39 Jesus *said, &amp;ldquo;Remove the stone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John 13:21-38</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/john-13.21-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/john-13.21-38/</guid>
      <description>Joh 13:21 When Jesus had said this, He became troubled in spirit, and testified and said, &amp;ldquo;Truly, truly, I say to you, that one of you will betray Me.&amp;rdquo;
Joh 13:22 The disciples began looking at one another, at a loss to know of which one He was speaking.
Joh 13:23 There was reclining on Jesus&amp;rsquo; bosom one of His disciples, whom Jesus loved.
Joh 13:24 So Simon Peter *gestured to him, and *said to him, &amp;ldquo;Tell us who it is of whom He is speaking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John 8:31-44</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/john-831-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/john-831-44/</guid>
      <description>Joh 8:31 So Jesus was saying to those Jews who had believed Him, &amp;ldquo;If you continue in My word, then you are truly disciples of Mine;
Joh 8:32 and you will know the truth, and the truth will make you free.&amp;rdquo;
Joh 8:33 They answered Him, &amp;ldquo;We are Abraham&amp;rsquo;s descendants and have never yet been enslaved to anyone; how is it that You say, &amp;lsquo;You will become free&amp;rsquo;?&amp;rdquo;
Joh 8:34 Jesus answered them, &amp;ldquo;Truly, truly, I say to you, everyone who commits sin is the slave of sin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marriage</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/marriage/</guid>
      <description>“BE FRUITFUL AND MULTIPLY AND FILL THE EARTH” Here we also see a major purpose of marriage: bearing children. This means that sexual intercourse is God’s invention, and pre-dated the Fall, so is part of God’s “very good” creation. But this is so only in its proper God-ordained context—marriage, which as shown above is only between a man and a woman: Let marriage be held in honor among all, and let the marriage bed be undefiled, for God will judge the sexually immoral and adulterous (Hebrews 13:4).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mothers of King of Judah</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/juda-kings-mothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/juda-kings-mothers/</guid>
      <description>Kings of Juda and their mothers# 1 Kings 14:16-
Micah 1:13
It is very interesting to note that the author of kings makes a point to mention every single Juda king&amp;rsquo;s mother except in the case of two kings; Jehoram and Ahaz.
Each is summed up as: &amp;ldquo;He walked in the way of the kings of Israel&amp;rdquo; (2 Kings 8:18, 16:3)
(2 kings 16:5-9, 15:19-20, 29, 17:3)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obedience of faith</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2015-02-15-obedience-of-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2015-02-15-obedience-of-faith/</guid>
      <description>Romans 16:26 - Obedience of Faith# I would like to take a moment to look at the phrase obedience of faith.
Before we look at what it means, and since Paul mentions this phrase at the beginning and at the end of the Epistle to the Romans, we should look at his purpose for writing:
``` So, for my part, I am eager to preach the gospel to you also who are in Rome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil 2:1-2 phrased</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/phil-21-2-phrased/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/phil-21-2-phrased/</guid>
      <description>===== Verses# Php 2:1 Therefore if there is any encouragement in Christ, if there is any consolation of love, if there is any fellowship of the Spirit, if any affection and compassion,
Php 2:2 make my joy complete by being of the same mind, maintaining the same love, united in spirit, intent on one purpose.
===== Sentences# Therefore if there is any encouragement in Christ, if there is any consolation of love, if there is any fellowship of the Spirit, if any affection and compassion, make my joy complete by being of the same mind, maintaining the same love, united in spirit, intent on one purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repentance According to the Bible</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2020-06-08-repentance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2020-06-08-repentance/</guid>
      <description>The term repentance comes with all sorts of different ideas. By doing a simple search on the internet we find it summed up in words like &amp;ldquo;remorse, contrition, contriteness, penitence, sorrow, regret&amp;rdquo;. Most would agree that this is what is meant when we use repentance/repent in our day to day use of the word. Probably the religious association is there for most. What I am tryng to look at in this note is how the Bible uses what we see translated as the word repentance in the English Bible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Romans 10:9-10</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/romans-109-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/romans-109-10/</guid>
      <description>Romans 10:9-10# Rom 10:8 But what does it say? &amp;ldquo;THE WORD IS NEAR YOU, IN YOUR MOUTH AND IN YOUR HEART&amp;rdquo;—that is, the word of faith which we are preaching,
Rom 10:9 that if you confess with your mouth Jesus as Lord, and believe in your heart that God raised Him from the dead, you will be saved;
Rom 10:10 for with the heart a person believes, resulting in righteousness, and with the mouth he confesses, resulting in salvation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The blood of Jesus</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/the-blood-of-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/the-blood-of-jesus/</guid>
      <description>The blood of Jesus# Brought Freedom# Zec 9:9 Rejoice greatly, O daughter of Zion! Shout *in triumph,*O daughter of Jerusalem! Behold, your king is coming to you; He is just and endowed with salvation, Humble, and mounted on a donkey, Even on a colt, the foal of a donkey.
Zec 9:11 As for you also, because of the blood of My covenant with you, I have set your prisoners free from the waterless pit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Warning to Timothy of False Teachers</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2020-06-09-the-attack-of-the-ephesian-false-teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2020-06-09-the-attack-of-the-ephesian-false-teachers/</guid>
      <description>But the Spirit explicitly says that in later times some will fall away from the faith, paying attention to deceitful spirits and doctrines of demons, by means of the hypocrisy of liars seared in their own conscience as with a branding iron,men who forbid marriage and advocate abstaining from foods which God has created to be gratefully shared in by those who believe and know the truth. 1 Timothy 4:1-3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Instructors</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2021-07-21-two-instructors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/2021-07-21-two-instructors/</guid>
      <description>Two Instructors# -by John Wry
The New Testament mentions two instructors, two trainers. One is referred to as instructor law and the other is referred to as instructor grace.
While it is true that law can mean the time period in which Israel lived and now we are under grace, that is not what I am referring to here. Law can mean many things namely; civil law, a principle, a specific law, 10 commandments, or legalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are Teaching &#39;Easy Believism&#39;</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/i-am-acused-of-teaching-easy-believism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/page/studies/topical/i-am-acused-of-teaching-easy-believism/</guid>
      <description>You are Teaching &amp;lsquo;Easy Believism&amp;rsquo;# Just recently, I received a kind accusation of teaching &amp;rsquo;easy believism&amp;rsquo;. I was asked three questions.
Are believers different to disciples? So, this is my more formal response - a work in progress but perhaps it might shed some light for others that are tragically caught in the midst of this divide.
First off, I ask myself, what do people mean by the term &amp;lsquo;easy believism&amp;rsquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
