<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Topics on BJWry</title>
    <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Topics on BJWry</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</webMaster>
    <copyright>The MIT License (MIT) Copyright © 2020 BJWry</copyright><atom:link href="https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/2015-03-24-predestination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/2015-03-24-predestination/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angels</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/angels/</guid>
      <description>Angels# When were angels created?# For by Him all things were created, both in the heavens and on earth, visible and invisible, whether thrones or dominions or rulers or authorities—all things have been created through Him and fo Thus the heavens and the earth were completed, and all their hosts. Gen 2:1
Angels were created by God. The question is when?
My contention is that the angels had to be created during the six days although the Bible doesn&amp;rsquo;t say explicitly which day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armageddon</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/armageddon-zech6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/armageddon-zech6/</guid>
      <description>My notes on Armageddon# Where does Armageddon come from?
It is a Greek translation of har-megiddo
Har means hill or mountain.
the the Valley of Jezreel is what lies near
HISTORY
Megiddo controlled a narrow strategic stretch of road called the Via Maris, &amp;ldquo;the Way of the Sea,&amp;rdquo; a major international highway in the ancient world. This road stretched from Egypt in the south to Babylon in Mesopotamia, linking the major empires and trade routes of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biblical Covenants</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/biblical_covenants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/biblical_covenants/</guid>
      <description>Biblical Convenants# Establishing a preliminary understanding# In order to arrive at a proper understanding of the biblical covenants, we will take a step back and see the general usage and importance of the term &amp;ldquo;covenant&amp;rdquo;.# Although we have many external sources (i.e. dictionaries, archaeological data, lexicons, historical records) that help us acquire a better understanding, we will not go to those first.# 2. A Scriptural principle: If the topic is to be considered important within the teaching of Scripture, the Bible will provide us sufficient usage and background to gain a sufficient understanding of that particular topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confession of Sins</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/confession-of-sins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/confession-of-sins/</guid>
      <description>Confession of Sins# What the Scripture teaches# Spiritual Separation# Then the LORD God called to the man, and said to him, &amp;ldquo;Where are you?&amp;rdquo; Genesis 3:9
Relational Separation# While the Father-child relation cannot broken with God, communion can.# When is fellowship broken between the believer and God?# 2Co 6:14 Do not be bound together with unbelievers; for what partnership have righteousness and lawlessness, or what fellowship has light with darkness?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with Pain</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/dealing_with_pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/dealing_with_pain/</guid>
      <description>Learning from Grief# It&amp;rsquo;s easy to doubt God when things don&amp;rsquo;t go well (Psalm 77:1-9) Knowing God&amp;rsquo;s true self provides a framework around our chaos (Psalm 77:10-14) Christ is our life (Psalm 77:15) Psalm 77# I. Psalm 77:1-6 Asaph doubts God# (For the choir director; according to Jeduthun. A Psalm of Asaph.)
Psa 77:1 My voice rises to God, and I will cry aloud; My voice rises to God, and He will hear me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discipleship -&gt; importance</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/discipleship-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/discipleship-need/</guid>
      <description>Discipleship# The Importance# Have you ever wondering why the apostle Paul writes an explanation of the Gospel to believers in Rome? Why does Paul clarify the Gospel to the Corinthian saints? Why would Paul defend the Gospel to the Galatian church? It seems redundant to waste words teaching the Gospel to believers.
I was once laughed at for articulating the Gospel to a family who was interested in our ministry. I tried to impress on them the need we saw of clarifying the Gospel to people in this generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ekklesia in the Bible</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/ekklesia-in-the-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/ekklesia-in-the-bible/</guid>
      <description>EKKLESIA = called out, called
Two other words in the ekklesia family are found in the Septuagint that are not in the New Testament: ekklesiazo the verb form “to call an ekklesia” and ekklesiastes the noun of agency “one who speaks to the ekklesia.”
ἐκκλησία G1577 in LXX# Deuteronomy 4:10 - on the day of the ekklesia. On this occasion God commanded Moses to “gather [the verb form of ekklesia] the people before Me”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homiletics</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/homiletics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/homiletics/</guid>
      <description>I. Content
- Providing clarity on the purpose of the passage - Analyzing the passage in context - Utilizing Bible references and supporting passages - Drives listeners back to the text of Scripture
II. Organization
- Provides an engaging introduction - Effectively traces the author&amp;rsquo;s flow of thought - Makes smooth transitions from point to point - Finishes with an effective conclusion
III. Rhetoric (the art of persuasion)
- Builds credibility, transparency, and personal examples - Connects well with listeners - Explains concepts using Scriptural reasoning</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperative verbs in Romans</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/imperative-verbs-in-romans-1-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/topical/imperative-verbs-in-romans-1-8/</guid>
      <description>Romans 1-8# Rom 3:4 May it never be! Rather, let God be found true, though every man be found a liar, as it is written, “That You may be justified in Your words, And prevail when You are judged.”
Rom 6:11 Even so consider yourselves to be dead to sin, but alive to God in Christ Jesus.
Rom 6:12 Therefore do not let sin reign in your mortal body so that you obey its lusts,</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
