<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Studies on BJWry</title>
    <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Studies on BJWry</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</webMaster>
    <copyright>The MIT License (MIT) Copyright © 2020 BJWry</copyright><atom:link href="https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 John</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/1-john/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/1-john/</guid>
      <description>====== What was from the beginning, what we have heard, what we have seen with our eyes, what we have looked at and touched with our hands, concerning the Word of Life— and the life was manifested, and we have seen and testify and proclaim to you the eternal life, which was with the Father and was manifested to us— what we have seen and heard we proclaim to you also, so that you too may have fellowship with us; and indeed our fellowship is with the Father, and with His Son Jesus Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 Peter</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/1-peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/1-peter/</guid>
      <description>1Pe 1:1 Peter, an apostle of Jesus Christ, To those who reside as aliens, scattered throughout Pontus, Galatia, Cappadocia, Asia, and Bithynia, who are chosen 1Pe 1:2 according to the foreknowledge of God the Father, by the sanctifying work of the Spirit, to obey Jesus Christ and be sprinkled with His blood: May grace and peace be yours in the fullest measure. Born Again to a Living Hope 1Pe 1:3 Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who according to His great mercy has caused us to be born again to a living hope through the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead, 1Pe 1:4 to obtain an inheritance which is imperishable and undefiled and will not fade away, reserved in heaven for you, 1Pe 1:5 who are protected by the power of God through faith for a salvation ready to be revealed in the last time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Timothy</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/2-timothy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/2-timothy/</guid>
      <description>2 Timothy# Greeting# 2Ti 1:1 Paul, an apostle of Christ Jesus by the will of God, according to the promise of life in Christ Jesus,
2Ti 1:2 To Timothy, my beloved son: Grace, mercy and peace from God the Father and Christ Jesus our Lord.
Guard the Deposit Entrusted to You# 2Ti 1:3 I thank God, whom I serve with a clear conscience the way my forefathers did, as I constantly remember you in my prayers night and day,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/ephesians/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/ephesians/</guid>
      <description>Go to Phrased Eph 1:1 Paul, an apostle of Christ Jesus by the will of God, To the saints who are at Ephesus and who are faithful in Christ Jesus:
Eph 1:2 Grace to you and peace from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.
Spiritual Blessings in Christ
Eph 1:3 Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places in Christ,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galatians</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/galatians/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/galatians/</guid>
      <description>The Book of Galatians# In the world we live in, the Sin Nature rules. It shows its ugly self through &amp;hellip;&amp;quot;immorality, impurity, sensuality, idolatry, sorcery, enmities, strife, jealousy, outbursts of anger, disputes, dissensions, factions, envying, drunkenness, carousing, and things like these&amp;hellip;&amp;quot; - Galatians 5:19-21
How do we deal with these issues in the church?
The compelling argument of the judaizing-missionaries to Galatia was to become jewish proselites. That is, the christian converts needed to become observers of the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galatians 3:21-29</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/gal-3.21-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/gal-3.21-29/</guid>
      <description>Gal 3:21 Is the Law then contrary to the promises of God? May it never be! For if a law had been given which was able to impart life, then righteousness would indeed have been based on law. Gal 3:22 But the Scripture has shut up everyone under sin, so that the promise by faith in Jesus Christ might be given to those who believe. Gal 3:23 But before faith came, we were kept in custody under the law, being shut up to the faith which was later to be revealed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habakuk</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/habakkuk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/habakkuk/</guid>
      <description>OUTLINE# Habakkuk complains to God (Hab 1:2-4) # God Responds (Hab 1:5-11) # Habakkuk questions God&amp;rsquo;s response (Hab 1:12-2:1) # God explains what He&amp;rsquo;s doing is truly just (2:2-20) # Habakkuk is reminded of God&amp;rsquo;s attributes and grace (Hab 3:1-16) # Habakkuk breaks out in an expression of worship (Hab 3:17-19) # Background # Habakkuk Asks God# 1 The pronouncement which Habakkuk the prophet saw: Habakkuk is a contemporary to Jeremiah, Zephaniah and probably lives during or soon after Josiah as king.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hebrews 3:1-6</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/hebrews-31-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/hebrews-31-6/</guid>
      <description>Heb 3:1 Therefore, holy brethren, partakers of a heavenly calling, consider Jesus, the Apostle and High Priest of our confession;
Heb 3:2 He was faithful to Him who appointed Him, as Moses also was in all His house.
Heb 3:3 For He has been counted worthy of more glory than Moses, by just so much as the builder of the house has more honor than the house.
Heb 3:4 For every house is built by someone, but the builder of all things is God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OT Books</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/ot-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/ot-books/</guid>
      <description>OT Books# Genesis/Beginnings,
Job/undeserved suffering,
Exodus/Redemption,
Leviticus/holiness,
Numbers/wandering,
Deuteronomy/repletion,
Joshua/conquest,
Judges/failure,
Ruth/beauty,
1 Samuel/transition,
2 Samuel/David’s reign,
Psalms/Praise,
1 Chronicles/Judah,
1 Kings/Division,
Proverbs/Wisdom,
Ecclesiastes/vanity,
Song of Solomon/marital love,
2 Kings/Captivity,
2 Chronicles/Judah,
Obadiah/Edom’s doom,
Joel/Judah’s judgement,
Jonah/hardheadedness,
Amos/Israel’s judgement,
Hosea/loyal love,
Micah/Judah’s judgement,
Isaiah/God’s servant,
Nahum/Nineveh’s doom,
Zephaniah/God’s judgement ,
Habakkuk/Faith perspective,
Jeremiah/final warning,
Lamentations/mourning,
Daniel/prophecy,
Ezekiel/visions,
Ezra/return,
Haggai/procrastination,
Zechariah/Messiah ,
Esther/providence,
Nehemiah/rebuilding,
Malachi/backsliding</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Romans 9-11</title>
      <link>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/romans-9-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>johnwry@gmail.com (BJWry)</author>
      <guid>https://johnwry.github.io/studies/books/romans-9-16/</guid>
      <description>In God&amp;rsquo;s Sovereignty, God is always just
Rom 9:1 I am telling the truth in Christ, I am not lying, my conscience testifies with me in the Holy Spirit, Rom 9:2 that I have great sorrow and unceasing grief in my heart. Rom 9:3 For I could wish that I myself were accursed, separated from Christ for the sake of my brethren, my kinsmen according to the flesh, Rom 9:4 who are Israelites, to whom belongs the adoption as sons, and the glory and the covenants and the giving of the Law and the temple service and the promises, Rom 9:5 whose are the fathers, and from whom is the Christ according to the flesh, who is over all, God blessed forever.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
